closing the project phase or iteration now
we're going to cover this in a lot more
detailed now too so various reasons
projects or phases can end the project was
successfully completed met the objectives
the project was canceled terminated
mentioned that before the deliverable
became obsolete and is no longer needed
that can happen too, especially with
technology changing so quickly.
Financing or resources are no longer
available.
Another project can be deemed more
important.
There goes your project.
Regulatory changes, mergers,
acquisitions, all reasons that
can stop projects and economic
and other external changes.
So note, I mentioned this before too.
The end of a phase is often
called a kill point or exit gate
where appropriate stakeholders
determine whether or not the
project should move
forward or is completed.
Canceled.
Transition readiness.
This is important too.
If objectives have been
met, we must plan to
transition to the end
of the project or phase.
We prepare transition planning artifacts
such as training and support documents.
That's really important.
We've got to make sure
that whoever we're going to
hand off the deliverables
too know how to use them.
So we'll determine the readiness of the
organization to start the transition,
end users, business teams, etc.
So steps in administrative closure,
we're talking all the paperwork.
So we need to obtain formal acceptance
from the customer.
And this will be for the project as a
whole.
All the deliverables
should have already been
created, verified and
accepted before we close.
So keep that in mind.
We'll move the deliverables, transition,
hand them over to operations or production
so that they'll make it out to the store
shelves.
Update and sign off on any outstanding
documents.
We've got to make sure everything has been
completed.
Again, before we release the team,
we'll do a final lessons learned.
We are doing lessons
learned throughout documenting
what's going well, what's not going well.
We'll do our final lessons learned as we
close the entire project.
We'll prepare the final project report
that will go out to our stakeholders.
We archive all the project documents.
So remember, the documents are called
artifacts.
We've been pulling from those OPAs this
entire time.
we have been contributing to them as well,
especially at the end,
all the project documents.
And once we do the lessons learn,
we'll formally release the team.
So the prior steps must be performed
regardless of how the project ended.
So if your project was terminated early or
there was a breach of contract,
for example, one side didn't do what they
were supposed to do, you still close.
you'll document what has been completed
and you will transition whatever
deliverables are done or even if you're
halfway through you'll document and
transition hand those over and some
organizations might have a project
termination checklist all right so with
predictive that's called a close out
meeting your final agile that's called a
retrospective So throughout the project
with Agile 2, you're documenting lessons
learned that at the end of each iteration,
that's called a respective,
at the end of the project, went
well, what didn't go well, and
are there ways we can improve?